[Melody of Golden Age]
[Episode 28]
Lord Yan.
So is there really no way
to bring the dead back to life?
There's too much injustice in this world,
especially towards women.
A woman has to obey her father at home,
and obey her husband after getting married.
All those rules of obedience and virtues.
If a woman made the slightest mistake,
she'd be despised by others,
and she'd be
drowned in spit.
Just think about it.
How ironic is this?
But if people only cling to these rules,
how can we ever achieve
true equality?
Xiuxiu.
How did you come to know Lord Mo?
And why do you call him Brother Mo?
He once saved me.
However,
perhaps at that time,
he had already
chosen me as a sacrifice.
You truly do resemble Mo Xiuxiu
to some extent.
But I'm
ultimately not Mo Xiuxiu.
Stop right there!
Don't move!
Jing Lin.
What's this about?
Release Lord Mo!
Mo Qianzhi colluded with the Fire Moth Cult,
abused his power, and killed innocent people.
The Imperial Security Bureau is here on imperial orders to arrest him.
Nonsense!
Lord Mo has been protecting the people
and fighting fiercely against the Half-faced Ghosts.
Back when he was executing the criminal Ji Dafu,
Grand Commander Shen, you repeatedly obstructed him.
It's not hard to see that you have ulterior motives.
Therefore, Lord Mo ordered us
to be on high alert.
Sure enough,
we've discovered that your group
[To Guangchun Hall]
has been secretly trading with the Half-faced Ghosts.
And now,
you're even kidnapping Lord Mo.
Are you trying to turn the tables on us?
You're framing us!
Ever Since Grand Commander Shen arrived in Yingzhou City,
the Half-faced Ghosts have been popping up like bamboo shoots
after a spring rain, one after another.
Could this also be a coincidence?
You're incredibly stupid.
You've all been
fooled by Mo Qianzhi's disguise!
Who exactly captured you?
Xiuxiu.
Come on, tell them the truth.
Mo Qianzhi is the one colluding with the Half-faced Ghosts
and wanting to use you
as sacrifices.
Shen Du.
It's been years since we last met.
I never expected
you'd become like this.
Surrender now!
You corrupt official!
Release Lord Mo immediately!
Mo Qianzhi is the one who condoned the Half-faced Ghosts
committing atrocities in the city.
He took advantage of
all your trust!
White Ghost!
Release Lord Mo at once!
Governor Mo is a
good official who cares for the people.
He always has the people's interests at heart.
Don't you frame him!
Release Lord Mo!
What are you doing?
Step back! Step back!
Don't harm the civilians!
We can't fight them,
and we can't reason with them.
These people of Yingzhou
have all gone mad.
Shen Du.
They've seen clearly
who's human and who's ghost.
What about you?
So this was your plan all along.
Wait!
Stop!
Sun Tan.
Are you constables trying to rebel?
My apologies, Lord Mo.
You all know
how tough we constables can be.
Everyone, step back! Step back!
Let them go!
Hurry, go! Let's go!
Thank you, General Sun, for coming to our rescue today.
Don't mention it, Grand Commander.
Commander Xu has sent me a letter,
ordering me to assist Secretary Yan with the investigation.
It was only natural for me to come and save you.
If it weren't for the constables' help today,
the people in the city,
with their spit alone,
would have drowned us.
For the people of Yingzhou,
Governor Mo is
a remarkable official.
During famine years, he set up porridge stalls
and distributed free porridge to the people.
On ordinary days, he led the yamen runners
to repair houses for the people
without charging a penny.
How could the common people
possibly think of such an official
as a bad person?
On one side, he's a benevolent person beloved by the people
and respected by his colleagues,
while on the other, he's a madman who disregards human life
and believes in a cult.
With these two sides of him,
it's indeed hard to distinguish.
For now, we can only hide outside the city
and wait to see what happens.
I'm sorry for the trouble
we brought to fellow constables,
having to be displaced here with us.
You're the people Commander Xu trusts.
I, the leader of constables
in Gannan Area,
trust you.
Grand Commander.
We just received a confidential letter.
It's from Xiang'an.
The Grand Empress Dowager has ordered
the troops from surrounding counties to gather.
She wants me and General Zhenyuan
to capture Mo Qianzhi alive together.
But Mo Qianzhi just sent people
to drive us out of the city.
This confidential letter arrived a bit too quickly.
Before coming here,
the Grand Empress Dowager summoned me,
ordering me to keep a close eye on Mo Qianzhi.
After I arrived in Yingzhou City,
a secret agent once made contact with me.
It was probably
Bi Qiu who was killed recently.
It's very likely
that he sensed something unusual
and sent the news to Xiang'an early on.
If that's the case,
it seems that everyone,
both inside and outside of the Cang State,
is under
the Grand Empress Dowager's surveillance.
This shows that
sending me to Gannan Area
to deal with the Half-faced Ghost incident
was also part of
the Grand Empress Dowager's calculations.
The Grand Empress Dowager
ordered you to capture Yingzhou City.
If there's going to be a battle,
what will happen to the civilians in the city?
I hope there will be a turn of events
before General Zhenyuan arrives.
Who's there?
Who is it?
Come out!
Qi Yeyun?
Sneaking around like that.
You just wanted to be dragged over here, didn't you?
This is what my sister taught me.
Always observe clearly first.
Caution is the parent of safety.
I, Shen Du, am here.
I have something to say to Mo Qianzhi.
If you want to talk,
come up and speak!
You really dare to come alone.
Aren't you afraid I'll kill you?
I'm here to give you
an ultimatum.
Xiang'an already learned about your betrayal.
The Grand Empress Dowager has dispatched the Zhenyuan Army
to send troops to Yingzhou.
It's not too late to back down now.
If they want to attack the city,
it won't be as easy
as they think.
Do you think
with the tens of thousands of citizens in the city
following you,
along with those few Half-faced Ghosts,
you can stand against the imperial court?
The will of the people
is worth ten thousand troops.
Do you still remember
the oath you took when you became my father's disciple?
To serve the country with utmost loyalty,
and to be worthy of the trust of all the common people under heaven.
Shen Du.
I really never thought
that one day, you would say such things to me.
Can't you see
that the current Cang State
is already crawling with parasites?
Its decay and collapse is only a matter of time.
Then remove these parasites,
instead of tearing it down.
The people of the Fire Moth Sect
have always disregarded human life
and could betray you at any moment.
Are you really going to use
the lives of these innocent civilians
to take this gamble?
If you want to negotiate,
we can.
Agree to one condition of mine.
What condition?
Bring Mrs. Shen's
head to me, and then we'll talk.
There's no room for negotiation then.
Du.
She works for the Grand Empress Dowager.
She's the Grand Empress Dowager's
tool to control you.
Without her,
you'll come to your senses
and see how devastated
the Cang State is now.
The one blinded by hatred
is you.
This time,
you're really wrong.
I'm wrong?
You clasped an enemy to your bosom.
Oh right,
she's the one with bosom.
What she eats every day
is delicacies stained red with the blood
of your people.
What she enjoys
is the wealth and glory built upon the bones
of your people.
If I'm wrong,
aren't you even more mistaken?
Don't you want to know the truth?
[Granary of Xiang'an, Cang State]
This is a sack for storing grain and fodder.
Why did the grain and fodder stamped with
the granary seal from back then
end up
in Gannan Area, which is a thousand miles away from Xiang'an?
[Granary of Xiang'an, Cang State]
Shouldn't these have been
destroyed by
the great fire back then?
Have you ever considered
that back then, my teacher,
your father,
was actually guarding
what was already
an emptied treasury?
I will uncover the truth myself.
But if you're to gamble with
the lives of the civilians of the city,
and to risk massacring an entire city
to establish your own foundation,
I cannot agree with that.
[Granary of Xiang'an, Cang State]
Stop this while you still can.
I don't have many people left in the world
that I'm close to.
[Granary of Xiang'an, Cang State]
I don't need your agreement.
The arrow is on the string and must be released.
I've been planning and enduring for so long.
I won't fail at the last moment.
I remember
you said you wanted revenge, didn't you?
Of course I want revenge,
but my father
and I
would never use
the lives of all the citizens in the city for revenge!
Grand Commander.
Shen Du.
How did the negotiation go?
There's no room for negotiation.
Jing Lin.
Where is General Zhenyuan now?
We've received word from neighboring Mengzhou.
The reinforcements should arrive in about three days.
This Mo Qianzhi.
Who knows how many troops he has amassed?
If it comes to that,
and all the male citizens in the city come to defend it,
it will surely be a fierce battle.
Not necessarily!
Mr. Pan, you're indeed efficient.
Grand Commander Shen.
I've brought all the items
you requested.
What are these?
What do you need these bamboo poles for?
A risky military strategy.
Success or failure hinges on this move.
[Cang]
You're not planning to
occupy Yingzhou City
before General Zhenyuan arrives, are you?
Brother Mo.
People often say
let bygones
be bygones.
But some pain
doesn't just exist in memory.
It's already deeply embedded in our flesh and blood.
It vibrates
with every breath,
constantly destroying
and cursing,
asking why I haven't died yet.
And those
who haven't truly experienced it,
how could they understand?
What right do they have to teach others
how to live?
Xiuxiu.
Do you think
I was wrong?
You're a good official
and a good brother.
You're the best person
I've ever met.
You're the one who
saved me from the pile of corpses.
Not only did you save me,
but you've also helped Yingzhou City a lot.
You haven't let anyone down.
It's this world
that owes you too much.
You're just like her,
always trusting me unconditionally.
But I've let you both down.
If one day
she really comes back to life,
I'm afraid she wouldn't recognize
what her brother
has become now.
If possible,
I'd really like to know
what the old you
was like.
[Yingzhou City]
Listen up, those above!
General Zhenyuan has led an army of 100,000 men here,
and they've reached the outskirts of the city.
They're here to protect the citizens
and wipe out the rebels.
This is the last chance for Yingzhou City.
Surrender, and your lives will be spared!
[Yingzhou City]
If you remain obstinate,
the traitors will be executed
to safeguard our people!
Lord Mo!
Lord Mo.
If war can be avoided,
I hope you can spare the lives of the citizens
in this city.
The current situation
is far beyond our expectations.
I've heard that General Zhenyuan
is cruel and belligerent by nature.
With the addition of these 100,000 reinforcements,
Yingzhou
will surely be destroyed in an instant today.
It will be a catastrophe for all living beings.
Indecisive.
Unlikely to achieve greatness!
Lord Mo.
My lord asked me to relay a message to you.
Now is the crucial moment to
change allegiances.
You must not
show womanly kindness.
The people of Fire Moth Sect
have always been ruthless with lives.
They might betray you at any moment.
Are you really going to gamble with
the lives of these
innocent civilians?
Lord Mo, for Yingzhou and its people,
would be willing to lay down his life,
yet he fell victim to the schemes of evil men.
We must protect Lord Mo
and protect Yingzhou City!
Protect Lord Mo!
Protect Yingzhou City!
You are a good official
and a good brother.
You're the best person
I've ever met.
In the end,
I've failed Yingzhou.
Protect Lord Mo!
Protect Yingzhou City!
[Yingzhou City]
Shen Du!
I, Mo Qianzhi,
challenge you to a duel!
We've finally come to this.
[Yingzhou City]
I taught you martial arts
when you were little.
In the past,
you've never beaten me.
You learned the move
I just taught you quite quickly.
Study diligently and practice earnestly,
only then can one make rapid progress.
One day,
I'll be able to defeat you.
Then you'd better hurry up.
I'm determined to become
the top military general of the Cang State,
galloping across battlefields
and serving the country with loyalty.
This time,
it's my turn to win.
What should we do?
Senior.
I'm indeed getting old.
My reflexes can't match yours anymore.
Protect Lord Mo!
You came to fight
because you couldn't bear to see
these people of Yingzhou lose their lives, right?
Open the city gate!
No need to fight anymore! Great!
[Cang]
What an impressive bluff.
Du.
Over these years,
you've indeed improved.
[Cang]
You've won.
If you had been a dispassionate observer,
you might have seen through this trick.
I was betting
that you wouldn't dare to risk
the lives of all the people in Yingzhou.
So,
you haven't really lost.
When will the reinforcements arrive?
Tomorrow.
Then when that time comes,
how will you explain to them?
Mo Qianzhi was controlled by a cult
and overestimated himself.
Yingzhou's military forces were scarce
and couldn't withstand a fight.
There are still many civilians in the city,
who believe that you are being
manipulated by the Fire Moth Sect,
pleading for mercy on your behalf.
Tell me,
how do you and the leader of the Fire Moth Sect
communicate?
People laugh at moths flying into the fire.
Moths go through fire and don't die;
they are reborn in the cycle.
The idea of resurrection is inherently a fallacy.
Heaven has the virtue of cherishing life.
Even mayflies that live for just a day
have their place
on the path of reincarnation.
How could they possibly not enter the cycle of reincarnation?
Moths flying through fire will only turn to ashes.
If they're unable to enter the cycle of reincarnation,
how could they be reborn?
The person you saw,
could it be Chen Huo'e?
I told you early on
not to get involved.
You don't know how deep the waters are
and insist on going your own way.
In fact, I never reported
the incident of Half-faced Ghost causing trouble.
Someone used my name.
From the very beginning,
you fell into someone else's trap.
What is this person's motive?
Until we reach Xiang'an
and see the Grand Empress Dowager,
I won't say anything.
No matter what,
you are still my senior.
Lord Yan!
Xiuxiu.
Lord Yan.
Why are you here?
Must Mo Qianzhi die?
When we reach Xiang'an,
the Grand Empress Dowager will make the final decision.
It's such a long journey.
May I give him some food?
Rest assured.
We'll surely
take good care of him on the way.
No matter what,
my name
was given by Brother Mo.
You came here
not just for this matter, right?
I beg you.
Help me.
Please help me.
Jing Lin!
I want to see Mo Qianzhi!
I'm different from those other girls
who were sacrificed.
I've know
what Brother Mo was planning to do.
I am willing!
Xiuxiu.
Stop it.
You shouldn't have come here.
Go back.
Xing.
Don't come any closer!
I came here just to see you
and talk to you for a bit.
Come to think of it,
those days with you around
were the happiest and most joyful days
of my entire life, Brother Mo.
If it weren't for you, Brother Mo,
I'd have been dead for a long time.
[Xiu]
Thank you for giving me a name.
[Xiuxiu]
Xiuxiu.
What a beautiful name.
Xiuxiu...
But I know,
every time you call
her name,
it's so different.
I know
there's only
one thing
you've always wanted
in your heart,
and that is to bring Xiuxiu back to life.
Brother Mo.
I'll be gone.
Xiuxiu!
Xiuxiu.
Xiuxiu. Xiuxiu!
Brother Mo.
Xiuxiu is here.
Xiuxiu...
Why are you so foolish?
Du!
Have everyone else leave.
Come here.
I have something to tell you.
Du.
I heard you were released from the Prisoner's Center,
and I heard that you've become
the Grand Commander of the Imperial Security Bureau.
I've also heard you've become cold-blooded and heartless,
cruel and vicious.
But I'm still glad.
You're the only survivor of the Shen family.
If you were still as gentle and easily bullied as before,
how could you avenge your father
and the entire Shen family?
After establishing the Imperial Security Bureau,
I've been investigating all along.
On the surface,
the evidence of the Shen family's case seems ironclad,
without any flaws.
But I still managed to find
some suspicious points.
What happened back then
couldn't have been done by one person alone.
My mentor, Shen Bingzhu, was naturally indifferent to worldly affairs.
He never wanted to get involved in court disputes.
He only cared about the common people.
No matter who was in what position,
he only did what he thought was right,
and all he wanted was for the people to be at peace.
But this very point
offended everyone else's interests.
The Grand Empress Dowager
you're so loyal to
wanted his submission.
Those who killed the entire Shen family
were the Zhou family.
I'll definitely uncover the truth
about what happened back then.
No matter how many years it takes,
and no matter who it is,
I will make them pay
one by one,
to comfort the souls
of the dozens of the Shen family members who died unjustly.
Du.
I never thought
that you and I would end up on opposite sides
because of the same hatred.
If you succeed one day,
remember to light an incense for me.
On my way to the underworld,
I can then rest in peace.
Senior.
Senior!
♫Grudges and debts, right and wrong♫
Behind Xiuxiu's painting,
♫The past is shrouded in blood and tears♫
there's something I want to give
♫It's been a long time since we parted♫
you...
♫Can't fully explain the true story♫
♫Fate twists and turns♫
Senior!
♫Life and death, fortune and misfortune, always intertwined♫
♫Obsession is hard to dispel, retain the true and discard the false♫
♫Let the wind blow♫
♫Through thick and thin, unwavering in heart♫
♫I'll be with you forever♫
♫At least I have you to share both joy and sorrow♫
♫Unravel fate, fearless and unyielding♫
♫A dream brings me back♫
♫The scenery is bright, hand in hand, we go back together♫
Ghost!
Karma has arrived. Karma has arrived!
As soon as Lord Mo passed away,
such a strange thing happened.
This is divine punishment!
It's poisoning.
Move aside.
Grand Commander.
There have been multiple incidents
of such bizarre occurrences in the city.
It's absolutely horrifying.
Over 30 civilians have been affected.
If this continues,
I'm afraid chaos will ensue.
This is the work of the Fire Moth Sect.
If we can't find a solution,
won't
the Fire Moth Sect conquer Yingzhou City
with just this poison?
And without shedding a drop of blood?
Although the toxicity of this poison is strong,
it takes time to take effect.
They won't be in immediate
danger for now.
I'll find a way
to get the antidote as soon as possible.
Yes.
Take care of things here.
Behind Xiuxiu's painting,
there's something I want to give you.